Garrett Listi

me@garrettlisti.com | 832.620.6306 | Pearland, Texas (Remote)

Summary

Senior full stack engineer with 11 years of experience in Fortune 20 companies leading in-person and remote engineering teams in the energy and technology industries. Passionate mentor and leader focused on growing those around me. Deep expertise in product and UX development.

Skills

Languages

Proficient with TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, Java, C#, HTML, SASS, CSS.

Familiar with C++, C, SQL

Tools and Frameworks

React, AWS, Flask, Node.js, Spring MVC, Webpack, Angular, jQuery, ASP.NET MVC, WPF, Cloud Development Kit (CDK), ARM Templates, Azure DevOps, Visual Studio, Git, Agile/Scrum, TDD, CI/CD

Experience

Microsoft Pearland, Texas (Remote)

Senior Software Engineer

May. 2024 — Present

Lead multi-team projects improving the performance and reliability of Azure Portal experiences impacting 1M+ MAU.

- Lead a large, multi-disciplinary team responsible for migrating the Azure Portal Create Virtual Machine experience from Knockout to React, improving Lighthouse metrics (TBT, LCP) by 10% while maintaining 99.9% reliability
- Successfully delivered the Azure Portal Compute Fleet experience to General Availability, working across product and design teams to plan and implement new feature and improvements
- Mentored team members in areas of technical and professional career development

Amazon

San Diego, California (Remote)

Senior Software Development Engineer

Feb. 2023 - May 2024

Lead the simplification of the public domain registration and customer acquisition flow for Amazon owned Top Level Domains.

- Lead the engineering, product and legal reviews of 3rd party owned critical path APIs, resulting in the on-time delivery of the next iteration of the Amazon domain activation funnel
- Developed engineering best practices including design document templates, design review agendas, and operational excellence guidelines, utilized by the engineering and product teams to foster better collaboration
- Designed and developed web services with Java Spring and AWS enabling 200+ monthly customers to activate newly purchased domains
- Planned and facilitated the execution of a service migration from services hosted on Amazon internal networks to AWS using modern architecture and infrastructure as code frameworks saving ~\$50k month over month
- Selected to mentor 4 mid-level engineers in areas of technical and professional career development

Senior Front End Engineer

Mar. 2022 — Feb. 2023

Responsible for solving complex under-the-roof operations architecture and business problems in order to build Amazon's Distribution Center Technology as a Service platform.

- Partnered with platform and application engineering teams to improve daily operations dashboard performance by 40% and data accuracy by 30%
- Lead feature development across the UX team and 5 engineering teams to ensure modern React front end development practices were employed and customer feedback incorporated
- Developed boilerplate components for hand-held device screens, reducing the time to develop new hand-held UIs by 30% and simplifying front end development for backend engineers
- Volunteered to mentor 3 junior engineers in areas of technical and professional career development leading to 2 promotions

Front End Engineer (Amazon Lab126)

Nov. 2019 — Mar. 2022

Built customer experiences for device Quality Assurance Engineers (QAEs) leveraging a React front end stack on top of Python services deployed to AWS.

- Developed and conducted 12 user interviews and ran a FireOS QAE community wide survey that identified 50+ UX deficiencies, baselining CSAT scores across all Device Testing DevOps services
- Redesigned user interfaces for 3 mission critical Device Testing DevOps services, improving CSAT by 20%
- Owned the FireOS test reporting service, maintaining an AWS server-less stack serving 250+ monthly users
- Consulted as an subject matter expert in product design for new initiatives across the Devices DevOps organization

ExxonMobil Houston, Texas

Lead Software Engineer

Jan. 2017 — Nov. 2019

Served as the web interfaces expert and back end services architecture design lead, enabling the surveillance, optimization and increased safety of production facilities.

- Designed and implemented a distributed scheduling system for predictive algorithms written in C# and Matlab
- Lead the practice of agile methodologies for a 12 member remote team through daily Scrum and Kanban
- Automated a CI/CD pipeline with Git and Azure DevOps, reducing the time to deploy the application by 90%
- Cofounded an enterprise wide developer community of 100+ members to mentor individuals and promote collaboration

Software Engineer Sept. 2014 — Jan. 2017

Developed web and desktop applications for an IT service team, focusing on simplifying and automating complex GIS tasks for customers and user support staff.

- Interfaced with customers, designers, and project managers to gather requirements, plan milestones and discuss progress on work items and bugs
- Designed a C# RESTful backend with AngularJS and WPF clients for a user content publishing system.
- Created C# and Python backend services to automate environment migrations and application health monitoring

Education

Texas A&M University - College Station, Texas - 2014

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Minor in Business Administration

Major GPA: 3.8, Overall GPA: 3.4